Guide to the Stanford Associates Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford Associates records
1934-2005
1934-1963
SC0833
Stanford Associates.
Stanford University. Stanford Associates.
4.5 Linear feet (11 boxes)
The bulk of the collection consists of minutes of the Board of Governors and the Executive Committee, 1934-63, with an index for the years 1942-55, and records from the "R" Planners dinner meetings, 1947-53. Other records include programs and other ephemera, 1951-92; miscellaneous correspondence, 1984-2005; resolutions awarded, 1966-85; newsletters, Feb. 1938-June 1956; and a bound copy of STANFORD ASSOCIATES, a series of brochures about the work of the University's various schools and departments, 1930s.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
This collection was received by the Stanford University Archives from the Stanford Associates in 2006 and 2007.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Stanford Associates is an honorary organization of 1500 Stanford alumni who have demonstrated significant and long-standing volunteer service to the University. Founded in 1934, Stanford Associates was originally responsible for volunteer fundraising for the University. Now a part of the Alumni Association, Stanford Associates has broadened its scope to honor exceptional alumni volunteer service from all areas of the University.
Description of the Collection
The bulk of the collection consists of minutes of the Board of Governors and the Executive Committee, 1934-63, with an index for the years 1942-55, and records from the "R" Planners dinner meetings, 1947-53. Other records include programs and other ephemera, 1951-92; miscellaneous correspondence, 1984-2005; resolutions awarded, 1966-85; newsletters, Feb. 1938-June 1956; and a bound copy of STANFORD ASSOCIATES, a series of brochures about the work of the University's various schools and departments, 1930s.
Access Terms
Stanford Alumni Association; Stanford University -- General subdivision--Finance.;; Stanford University. Stanford Associates.
Collection Contents
- Records, Accession ARCH-2006-215
  - Board of Governors, bound minutes, 1934 Sep-1941 Jun (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Board of Governors, bound minutes, 1941 Oct-1947 Jun (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Board of Governors, bound minutes, 1947 Oct-1950 Jun (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Board of Governors, bound minutes, 1950 Oct-1953 May (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Board of Governors, bound minutes, 1953 Sep-1956 May (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Index to Minutes 1942-1955: I-V (Administration, Financial, Formation, Meetings, Membership) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Index to Minutes 1942-1955: VI-VIII (Program, Publications, Relations) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Index to Minutes 1942-1955: IX-X (Stanford Fund, List of Board of Governors) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Meetings: Board of Governors and Executive Committee, 1934-1936 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Meetings: Board of Governors and Executive Committee, 1936-1937 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Meetings: Board of Governors and Executive Committee, 1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Meetings: Board of Governors and Executive Committee, 1938-1939 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Meetings: Board of Governors and Executive Committee, 1939-1940 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Meetings: Board of Governors and Executive Committee, 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Minutes: Board of Governors and Executive Committee, 1956 Feb-1961 Oct (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Minutes: Board of Governors and Executive Committee, 1962 Jan-1963 Nov (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Executive Committee minutes, 1934-1939 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Executive Committee minutes, 1940-1946 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Executive Committee minutes, 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Executive Committee minutes, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Executive Committee minutes, 1950-1951 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Membership Committee, lists and reports, 1938-1950 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Address by Donald Tresidder, 1944 May 22 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Address by Homer Spence, 1951 Jan 19 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Luncheon meeting, Los Angeles, 1945 Oct 23 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Spring luncheon meeting, San Francisco, 1946 May 27 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - "R" Planners dinner meeting, San Francisco, 1947 Mar 17 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - "R" Planners dinner meeting, Los Angeles, 1947 May 12 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - "R" Planners dinner meeting, San Francisco, 1948 Mar 15 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Pre-inaugural dinner honoring Dr. Sterling, San Francisco, 1949 Oct 6 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - "R" Planners dinner meeting, David Starr Jordan Centennial Year, San Francisco, 1951 Jan 19 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - "R" Planners dinner meeting, David Starr Jordan Centennial Year, extra copies of material filed (including transcript of Gov. Earl Warren's remarks) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - "R" Planners dinner meeting, honoring Lloyd Dinkelspiel [and awarding first uncommon man award to Paul C. Edwards], San Francisco, 1953 Dec 8 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Awards ceremonies (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Award forms, blank (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Centennial medallion, 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Citations (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1984-2005 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Directory, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - 50th anniversary, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Gold Spike Award (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Programs, invitations from non-award events (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Programs from two early events, 1953-1956 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Resolutions (to individuals), 1966-1985 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Uncommon Man, 1951-1984 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Stanford Associates: a series of brochures about the work of the University's various schools and departments, 1930s (bound, 2 copies) (Box 7)
  - Stanford Associates Newsletter, Feb. 1938-June 1956 (bound) (Box 7)
  - Oversize certificates, awards, resolutions (including a few blank forms) (Box 8)
  - Reproductions of 3 Stanford Daily front-pages re Peter Bing, 1954-1955 (Box 8)
- Additional Records, Accession ARCH-2007-072
  - Stanford Associates Directories, 1938-1990 (Box 1)
  - Advertising program, newsprint samples, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
  - Creative Committee (The Stanford Fund), 1959-1972 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - End of Centennial Publication records, with historical sources, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Gold Spike selection process, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - History and development of Stanford Associates, 1950-1955 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - History and development of Stanford Associates, 1942-1949 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Long Range Planning Committee, two reports, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Peck, T. and Grace, K., "The Long Bench", 1987 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Report on a Study of the Feasibility of Establishing a Speakers Bureau at Stanford, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Resolutions re individual members, 1966-1980 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Tribute to Cuthbertson, records re, 1976-1984 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Tribute to Cuthbertson, copies of congratulatory letters, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Uncommon Man quote (H. Hoover) on parchment (multiple copies) (Box 3, Folder 5)